<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on ~/.monesonn</title>
    <link>https://monesonn.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on ~/.monesonn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Stanislav</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 10:07:34 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://monesonn.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>101.Artix</title>
      <link>https://monesonn.github.io/posts/artix-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 10:07:34 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monesonn.github.io/posts/artix-installation/</guid>
      <description>Artix [The Art of Linux] - systemd-free GNU/Linux distribution. It uses OpenRC, runit or s6 as init system.
Basically, it&amp;rsquo;s fork of the Arch with minimal differences, it&amp;rsquo;s almost the same, but there is an option of runit system (due to it, few Arch packages might not be available yet).
Below I&amp;rsquo;ll put link. There are you find external links and information against systemd, and why you should use Artix Linux or similiar distributions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>101.Suckless Editing</title>
      <link>https://monesonn.github.io/posts/vi-edit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monesonn.github.io/posts/vi-edit/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to editing files, I would definitely recommended any VI-like editors [Vim/Neovim]. They are pretty simple and functional as the Swiss knife. They can be used directly from the terminal and compared to other editors, they more faster and better cope with different types of files. The mastering itself, I would describe the Bushnell Citation: &amp;ldquo;Easy to learn, hard on the master.&amp;rdquo; Knowledge of it will never be superfluous and only depends on you how useful it can be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>101.Suckless Slides</title>
      <link>https://monesonn.github.io/posts/pandoc-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 15:47:13 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monesonn.github.io/posts/pandoc-slides/</guid>
      <description>Not so long ago I faced the problem that it&amp;rsquo;s quite difficult for me as a student to make presentations quickly and with high quality. Using Google Slide or similar services was not the best solution for me. For now, I won&amp;rsquo;t explain it yet.
So, alternatively, I started to use: Pandoc + Beamer bundle.
 Pandoc is a free and open-source document converter written on Haskell. Beamer is a LaTeX document class for creating presentation slides, with a wide range of templates and a set of features for making slideshow effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://monesonn.github.io/posts/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monesonn.github.io/posts/intro/</guid>
      <description>.:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:.:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:.:~:.
This is my first site using Hugo. So, it&amp;rsquo;s looks kinda good for me. The idea of &amp;ldquo;compiling&amp;rdquo; a static site using .md looks convenient for writing documentation for some pet projects. I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll use it for this blog page until something interesting appears.
.:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:.:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:..:~:.:~:.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
